# **Toby Jake Donaldson**

+44(0)7717413733 / toby.j.donaldson@gmail.com / https://uk.linkedin.com/in/tobyjdonaldson

I help businesses solve problems and create ideas that get them ahead.

I've worked with one person start-ups and FTSE100 businesses. From finance to FMCG, recycling to religious texts, heavy industry to HIV/AIDS, and in the tech, consulting, agency, and start-up worlds.

I started life in behavioural science and psychology but my career has taken me into strategy, creative consulting, and sustainability work all around the world. I also work on a handful of side / pro-bono projects with friends, colleagues, non-profits, and collectives.

When not working - I'm most likely rucking my way up a large hill, or bobbing around offshore in a wetsuit.`

# **Employment**

# Feb 2023 - Ongoing: Strategy Partner, Fox + Hare, London, UK

Same as the below - but with a bigger list of clients, more responsibility, and a slice of equity. I still make the tea.

## March 2022 - Feb 2023: Strategy Director, Fox + Hare, London, UK

I head up and run the strategy at proudly independent creative agency / sustainability consultancy Fox + Hare. Our work spans full service creative and strategy, sustainability, consulting, and positive impact. I'm responsible for consulting, strategy, sustainability, creative + copy, new biz and marketing. I also make the tea.

Clients: easyJet Holidays, Pepper Money, OneID, Vestiaire Collective, The Big Issue and many more.

## Nov 2021 - March 2022: Principal Consultant, Archetype Brands, London, UK

I was principal consultant at Archetype Brands (part of Next15 group) is a Southwark based agency working with primarily US clients - focused on 'creating magnetic brands'.

Clients: Brightly (formerly Dude Solutions), FinThrive (formerly nThrive).

#### Feb 2021 - Nov 2022: Senior Consultant, Radley Yeldar, London, UK

Radley Yeldar is an award winning creative consultancy in the heart of London's East End. We specialise in behaviour change, brand, campaigns, strategy and sustainability - and most importantly, bringing 'belief to business'.

Clients; WRAP, ViiV Healthcare, Positive Action, GSK, Wood Group, Syngenta, Great Portland Estates, BP, Shell Marine, BAT, Ferrero, Driscoll's & the Luc Hoffmann Institute.

# Feb 2019 - Feb 2021: Consultant, Radley Yeldar, London, UK

Clients; Kaspersky, WRAP, Recycle Now, Love Food Hate Waste, GSK, ViiV & Positive Action, Wood Group, HS2, Syngenta, Great Portland Estates, BP, Shell Marine, BAT, Tetra Pak and the Bible Society.

# June 2018 - Feb 2019: Strategic Planner, MRM // McCann, London, UK

MRM // McCann is a leading full service agency with a focus on customer relationships and an integrated part of the wider McCann Worldgroup. I was also sent to Costa Rica by McCann and Raleigh International to design and run a course on campaigning, strategy, government lobbying and behaviour change as part of 'Out of Office for Good'. Overseen by the British ambassador to Costa Rica & Nicaragua.

Clients: TSB, Cisco, Vauxhall, GSK, Macmillan Cancer Support, Saudi Aramco, Microsoft.

## May 2017 - May 2018: Junior Planner, MRM // McCann, London, UK

Clients: TSB, Cisco, Vauxhall, GSK, Macmillan Cancer Support, Saudi Aramco, Microsoft.

# January 2017 - April 2017: Junior Strategist (Contract), ZAK, London, UK

ZAK is a Farringdon based independent creative agency with a singular focus: generating big brand ideas that engage under 30s. Set up and ran the Global Insight Network (GIN), developed and wrote trend reports, sourced and managed contributors. Alongside standard new biz and strategy work. Facebook and Google were both subscribers.

Clients: New Balance.

## August 2016 - November 2016: Online Marketing (Contract), Lamudi. Berlin, Germany

Lamudi is an online real estate marketplace operating in 34 countries.

Responsible for setting up and running online marketing operations for the Mexico, Peru, Philippines and Pakistan markets. Mexican and Philippine markets are now the 1<sup>st</sup> and 3<sup>rd</sup> largest for Lamudi globally. Used data, insight, research, and social listening to develop digital creative over a wide range of media channels globally, while liaising with local teams and clients worldwide. Copy + strategy.

## July 2015 - July 2016: Field Specialist, Apple. (Contract) Global

Part of a team of 10 based out of London, working on the ground in 11 countries and in 12 languages. Indefinite NDA.

Responsible for planning, troubleshooting, and problem solving - working with teams in the UK, US & Japan. Working covertly worldwide, on assignments using unreleased Apple hardware / software. Field and 'lockdown' office work included in this.

Previous; KRM-PER, Compass Group, Scandlines Sverige, the Club Company, G4S, Merchant's Bar, Brindley & Co Solicitors.

# **Education**



#### Autumn 2021: CISL Business Sustainability Management - University of Cambridge (Cambridge, UK)

The Cambridge Institute for Sustainability Leadership works with business, government and civil society to build the capacity of leaders both to meet the needs of society and to address critical global challenges.



# Sept. 2013 – Oct. 2015: Marketing MSc (Academic Scholarship) - Instituto Universitário de Lisboa (Lisbon, Portugal)

Master of Science in Marketing.

- Key courses: Branding, Consumer Behaviour, Strategic Brand Management, Relationship Marketing & Communications.
- Thesis: 'Brand Love & the Ideal Self: An Investigation into Anthropomorphic Function in Brand Love' (published and available on <u>Amazon</u>).
- Al Portuguese Language.



# May 2015 - Oct. 2015: Sustainability MSc - Lunds Universitet (Lund, Sweden)

6 month exchange.

- Key courses: CSR, Innovation Management, Sustainability, Scandinavian Models of Equality.
- Al Swedish Language.



## Sept. 2010- June 2013- Psychology BSc - University of Leeds (Leeds, UK) (2.1)

Bachelor of Science in Psychology.

- Key courses: Advanced Social Psychology, Memory & Language, Cognitive Neuroscience, Personality & Intelligence, and Psychology in the Media.
- Dissertation 'Conceptual Combinations; Forming Impressions of Brand Extensions'.

# **Training/Certifications**

- Facebook, Google, APA, IPG McCann, Effectiveness BPS and various strategy / creative courses.
- CISL Business Sustainability Management course (University of Cambridge 2021)
- Other; Tier 1 Medic RLSS.